<Document>
  # USSP Overview

  The [color=yellow]Union of Soviet Socialist Planets[/color] is a weakened but still enduring worker-state born from the collapse of the old corporate order, the contradictions of the well-intentioned but short-lived Confederacy, and the revolutionary schism that began on Nova Cygni. It lost the civil war to the TSF, but it was not wholly destroyed. What remains is a reduced, more cautious, and more secretive Union, still held together by ideology, central institutions, and a deeply instilled belief that collective purpose will outlast private ambition.

  The USSP was forged in opposition to the age that came before it. To the Union, the Corporate War proved that greed, private power, and compromise with the old order could only lead to ruin. [color=yellow]Nova Cygni[/color] became the birthplace of the Revolution and remains the political and symbolic heart of the state to this day. Even after defeat, that founding memory continues to shape the Union’s identity, its institutions, and its hostility towards the [color=cyan]TSF[/color], which it views not only as a rival power, but as the victorious inheritor of too much of the world the Revolution was meant to destroy.

  The modern USSP is more bureaucratic, politically strained, and cautious than the revolutionary Union that first forged it. The death of the [color=gold]Autarch[/color] and the end of the old wartime order did not erase the state, but transformed it. In place of singular revolutionary rule came a more collective and procedural system, though one still marked by centralisation, ideological seriousness, and deep fear of further decline. The result is a Union that is less openly dominant than it once was, but often more brittle, more secretive, and more willing to gamble in search of leverage it can no longer secure through conventional strength alone.

  For ordinary citizens, servicemen, and officials alike, the Union remains more than a defeated cause. It is a living state with its own society, armed forces, and traditions, sustained by discipline, memory, and the belief that history has not yet finished with it. Though diminished in strength, the USSP remains a consequential power whose influence extends beyond its present borders, and whose choices may yet shape the future of the sector in ways both subtle and severe.

</Document>
