<Document>
  # USSP Remnants

  The [color=yellow]Union of Soviet Socialist Planets'[/color] 78th Expeditionary Fleet and its attached 13th Naval Infantry Battalion were once tasked with securing the Colossus Sector under Operation Roundtable. The expeditionary fleet was shattered by a sudden and disorganised withdrawal order, with much of it lost in the retreat through the far fringes of the sector.

  The Remnants no longer find themselves in open conflict with either the [color=cyan]TSFMC[/color] or [color=gold]PDV[/color], with both powers too burdened by their own conflict to completely destroy what remains of this weakened but stubborn force.

  Cut off from their distant home and left without further orders from USSP Naval Command, the survivors now endure in isolation. The Naval Infantry, burdened by sustained losses and threadbare leadership, remain a battle-tested but increasingly strained force. Held together by camaraderie, pride, and the stubborn belief that their sacrifice must still have meaning, the Remnants now struggle to preserve what remains, some holding fast to the hope that one day the Union will return, while others begin to doubt that it ever will.

  The detachment's overall objectives, as briefed by Naval Command before deployment to the Colossus sector, are to:

  > Secure Camelot as a centre of operations

  > Maintain workable relations with neutral and non-hostile groups

  Detailed objectives for the everyday infantryman will be outlined by the Commissar in charge as situations unfold, but with the detachment largely cut off from Naval Command and the outer sectors of Union space, the immediate task is clear: survival. The men and women of the 13th may be called upon to fend off anomalous threats, recover resources from debris and wreckage, and study relevant technology to strengthen their local military capacity. Only through discipline, loyalty to the Party, and unity can one expect to endure in this unforgiving sector.


  # The Chain of Command

  Within the USSP Armed Forces, [color=gold]Commissars[/color] make up the entirety of the formal officer corps. Drawn from the Commissariat and assigned across the branches, they hold command authority while also maintaining discipline, morale, and ideological direction.

  A Commissar is expected to embody the authority and ideals of the Union, and to ensure that military force remains tied to political purpose. For a Commissar, service to the state is service to the people; they are expected to carry that pride visibly, and to serve as a sign to their comrades of what unwavering dedication to the Union can become.

  In practice, their quality as military commanders varies widely. Some are hardened leaders shaped by real service, while others are more bureaucratic than martial, spending more time behind a console than standing before an infantry formation.

  For the Remnants of the 13th, isolation and hardship have shaken the once-great pride and unity of the ranks. The few remaining Commissars stand as the last reminder of the will of the State. Left only with their original mission and silence from their distant home, they now face the labour of unifying the battalion under a common purpose once more.

  The [color=darkyellow]Serzhants[/color] Within the Naval Infantry, a Serzhant is usually among the longest-serving and most reliable comrades in a battalion, trusted not only by their superiors, but by the ranks themselves.

  Promotion to Serzhant is formally initiated by a Commissar, who selects the candidate, but it must then be confirmed through private vote within the battalion, reflecting the common belief across the Armed Forces that leadership among the ranks must be earned as well as granted.

  In practice, Serzhants serve as the bridge between Riflemen and the Commissariat: enforcing standards, carrying hard-won wisdom, and often acting as the voice of reason between the line and command. In battle, Serzhants act as squad leaders and, in the Naval Infantry especially, are often the only leadership physically present among the ranks, with the Commissariat usually commanding remotely through USSP STRATCOMM.

  Among the Remnants of the 13th especially, where losses and isolation have thinned formal leadership, the burden of their responsibility has only grown heavier.

  [color=yellow]Riflemen[/color] The USSP Naval Infantry are not just regular soldiers assigned to ships, but a distinct branch of the Union’s Armed Forces. Separate from the People’s Army and closely intertwined with the Navy, they are trained for boarding actions, small-unit tactics, and the many brutal realities of void warfare.

  The Naval Infantry were founded in the years following the Revolution against the newly forming TSF. During the struggle, the iconic large infantry formations fielded by what would become the People’s Army, while effective in ground combat, proved ill-suited to the realities of fighting in space.

  Once deployed to a theater by the Navy, Naval Infantry units are expected to operate with considerable independence, supported by their own smaller craft and steadfast branch culture.

  Within the USSP military, they are seen as one of the most demanding and prestigious branches, defined by discipline, cohesion, and the expectation that they live up to the prestige placed upon them by the Union.

  # Gear

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponShotgunBigLeady"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRifleAK502"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponDP29"/>
  </Box>

  The USSP's ground combat doctrine involves primarilly ballistic weapons, namely the AK weapons platform along with 4 gauge shotguns and light machine guns.

  [color=green]Strengths:
  - USSP weapons for the most part use a variety of common calibers.
  - Their 4 gauges can load flashbangs, useful for disorientating chimeras and other OPFORs
  - Their research grants insight into a wider array of explosives.

  [color=red]Weaknesses:
  - The 9mm and 7.39mm cartridges used in standard firearms lack a bit of firepower compared to their larger counterparts.
  - The DP29 lacks the ammo capacity that the Ratel and Grizzly possess.
  - Inadequate anti-mech response outside of 12 and 4 gauge slugs.
  - What you see is generally what you get, lacking any of the fancy schticks TSF or PDV weapons possess.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitUsspL27"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingModsuitUSSPZastavnik"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetHeavyUSSP"/>
  </Box>

  The 13th Naval Infantry makes use of general purpose hardsuits, with a couple of MODsuits mixed in.

  [color=green]Strengths:
  - The L-line of suits all have MEDhuds, allowing for a slightly more diverse eye loadout.
  - The Varyag and Zastavnik MODsuits allow the flexible use of ground combat armors or lighter, less protected hardsuits. The Zastavnik in particular has HUD modules.

  [color=red]Weaknesses:
  - Their armors don't quite reach the durability of the Cybersuit Juggernaut Suits nor do they possess integrated shields.
  - They lack diagnostic HUDs, sorry IPCs.

</Document>
